Ivan Yurev

+7 (967) 065-92-33 | ivan.yuriev@qmail.com | Moscow, Russia

Software Engineer

Visa Sponsorship Required

PROFILE

Software engineer with 12+ years of experience in different areas of software development specializing in .NET with C# but open for new top-notch technology. A team player who values respectful discussions, knowledge sharing, and collaborative problem solving and understands the worth of business goals and the balance between trade-offs. Considering relocation in the EU, USA, Canada, and Australia.

TECHNOLOGIES

Backend: .NET, C#, T-SQL, PowerShell, Lua

Frontend: JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, WPF, ASP.NET

Databases: MS SQL Server, Couchbase, Elastic search, Gigaspaces, Redis, InfluxDB, SQLite

Technologies: .NET Core, Entity Framework, xUnit, ELK, LINQ, WCF, WPF

Protocols: RESTful, JsonAPI, GraphQL, gRPC, SSE, SOAP, OData, Swagger, OpenTelemetry

Architecture: Microservices, SOA, CQRS, Event Sourcing, GoF patterns, POSA, Messaging and Streaming, N-Tier

EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Developer | <u>avionero.com</u> | Malmö, Sweden (remotely)

2017 - 2020

Built entire IT infrastructure for early-stage start-up in the flight search industry:

- Designed internal components for the microservices-based solution
- R&D an efficient yet flexible microservices API conventions
- Integrated and configured infrastructure for logging, monitoring, troubleshooting, CI/CD practices
- Designed and implemented relational and NoSQL data storages
- Developed business features for high-load, distributed, fault-tolerant solution
- Involved in project management: roadmap, feature planning, task decomposition, solution improvements
- Technologies: .NET Core, C#, SQL Server, Couchbase, Microservices, ELK, IIS

Software developer | mahjongtime.com | San-Diego, USA (remotely)

2012 - 2017

As a full-stack developer worked on supporting existing and appending new features for online multiplayer game:

- Successfully and smoothly migrate legacy system with 500K+ users and 10K+ RPM
- Integrated with a big variety of external resources: payment systems, facebook, google ads, etc.
- Planned a new features implementation with the business side
- Significantly improved project stability with automated testing (including stress testing)
- Detected performance bottlenecks and improved performance
- Supported and improved the solution structure with best practices: GoF patterns, TDD, SOLID principles
- Improve unit tests with proper code coverage for regression testing

• <u>Technologies</u>: .NET 2.0-4.5, C#, SQL Server, Gigaspaces XAP, Reporting services, NAnt scripts, ASP.NET WebForms

Software developer | Freelance | Moscow, Russia

2010 - 2012

ODesk (Upwork) freelancer working on small and medium-sized solutions from scratch and as a supporter:

- Kinect-based game for children to improve tactile skills
- Participation in .net based CMS development
- Kinect-based Unity3D interactable presentation for Annual Siberia Region Forum
- E-book for UNICEF based on WPF
- iOS application for <u>makeuseof.com</u>
- Participation in Windows Phone application development for geophrasebook.com
- <u>Technologies</u>: C#, .NET, Objective-C, Unity3D, Kinect, WCF, WPF, MySQL, MS SQL Server, Silverlight

Founder | Logicon IBS | Bishkek, Kyrgyz Republic

2006 - 2010

E-commerce software for financial/e-trading companies and specific hardware like ATMs, cash-in kiosks, pocket PCs

- Team leading for a rapidly growing team with different levels of knowledge
- Estimating, planning, scheduling projects, and managing deadlines
- Establishing and improving communication between different departures inside the company
- Leading back-end department based on Agile, TDD, Extreme Programming practices
- Customer negotiation
- Writing code :)
- <u>Technologies</u>: C#, C++, Javascript, .NET, CEN/XFS, MS SQL Server, SSRS, SSIS, Windows Mobile, Windows Embedded, Ajax, Sharepoint Server, Axapta, different hardware APIs

EDUCATION

Specialist/Bc.S of Computer Science | Kyrgyz State Technical University | Bishkek, Kyrgyz Republic

2001 - 2006

- Undergraduate Scholar Program Scholarship by the Government of Kyrgyz Republic
- Graduate with honors, an average GPA of 92%
- Lecturing WinAPI programming for 1 year after graduation

PROFILES

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivan-yuriev-aab28425

Github: https://github.com/lvanYuriev

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/1336056/ivan-yuriev

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/ivan.yuriev.9

Email: ivan.yuriev@gmail.com